JULIAN VALLE

FRONT END WEB DEVELOPER

Oct. 2019

SUMMARY

Javascript developer with experience working in React. I can start from wireframe to prototype, all the way to final product bringing high quality, fast, responsive websites for clients. I come from a nontraditional background of psychology which gives me a keen insight into client needs and a deeper understanding of user behavior in order to deliver tailor made user experiences and designs.

CONTACT

- **■** jvalle0926@gmail.com
- theuncannyvalle.com
- **(**805) 825-8686
- **Q** Los Angeles
- ★ theuncannyvalle
- in uncannyvalle
- uncannyvalle

EDUCATION

Fresno State University Psychology B.A.

Fall 2011 to Winter 2014

PROJECTS

Atole Media

A web site made for a video game startup using Gatsby. This was my first time attempting Gatsby and deploying to Netlify which taught me more about React components, using CSS in JS and learning more about the React lifecycle.

Lena's Videotheque

A blog site I made using a Gatsby template. It uses markup files in order to make new blog posts.

Movie Quote Generator

Made using Create-React App. Worked using API and had to learn more about the React lifecycle and file organization.

Markdown Previewer

An app that translates markdown files and allows you to preview how they might look in your website.

The Adventures of Danny Boy

Helped make the game using jQuery in a school project. Worked on the timer, game mechanics and cursor positioning.

SKILLS

FRONT END: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React, SASS/SCSS, Git, Windows, Mac

MISC: Slack, Team Organization, Agile Methodologies, G Suite

AWARDS

freeCodeCamp.org · Responsive Web Design Certificate Sept. 2018 Certificate showing I completed 300 hours of learning Responsive web design using HTML and CSS

freeCodeCamp.org · Aug. JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures 2019
Certifies 300 hours completed working on Javascript algorithms

EMPLOYMENT

Freelance

Web Developer Jan. 2019 to Current Designed, built and deployed web sites for small businesses.

Helping Hands Behavioral Solutions
Behavioral Therapist
Glendale, CA
Feb. 2019 to Feb. 2020

Child Counseling and Behavioral Therapy Clinic Encino, CA Behavioral Therapist Jan. 2017 to Jan. 2019